Jazer Barclay

Portfolio: www.jazer.dev Email: contact@jazer.dev LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jazer-barclay Mobile: 07759 228812

Profile

Second year Computer Science student at the University of Brighton focusing on full stack development, scalable infrastructure and machine learning; currently looking for an industry placement.

I am a self-motivated and disciplined professional with strong knowledge of self-hosting, software development and best practices combined with over 10 years of education and formal work experience.

Technical Skills

- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- NodeJS
- Linux
- Java
- PostgreSQL
- Git & GitHub
- CD / CI & Agile

Education and Qualifications

University of Brighton, Computer Science (BSc Hons)

Sept 2020 – July 2024

- On track for a 1st after achieving 70% and above in all first year modules, including 100% in computing technologies and an 81% year average
- **Student representative** for first year, assisting students through remote learning and providing personal support in my spare time

Modules include:

- Introduction to web development (89%) For our first year we covered HTML, CSS and JavaScript. With this we created a learning journal documenting our progress and serving as a markable piece. Live Demo
- Introduction to Programming (77%) With a focus on Java and object oriented programming paradigms we were tasked with upgrading skeleton code for a breakout inspired game or to do a freestyle project. I chose to build a space invaders clone using JavaFX following the MVC design pattern and tracked all my code and report on GitHub.
- Working in the computing industry (76%) For this module we worked in teams
 of 3 in order to create a cyber security website aimed at students in their first year
 of secondary school I took on the roles of project manager and developer using
 project management and collaboration tools including Trello, GitHub, Notion and
 Microsoft Teams. Live Demo

Java 8 Developers Course (London)

Dec 2016

 Completed a course covering Java 8, lambda functions, net beans, Eclipse, agile development and git version control.

Bexhill College

Sept 2011 – July 2014

• A Levels: Electronics (B), IT (C), Computing (D)

Claverham Community College

Sept 2011 - July 2014

• GCSEs: 10 at grades A - C including Science (A), English (B) and Maths (B)

Work Experience

Senior Technician & Lead Developer

July 2017 – June 2020

Tora Tech, Sidley

- Full time software developer designing and building bespoke websites driving sales up by up to 20% and providing a greater online presence for new businesses.
- Supported businesses and residential customers with technical support via remote and on-site assistance for hardware repairs, upgrades and installations.
- Maintained Linux and Windows Servers facilitating 99% uptime with the remaining 1% being for scheduled maintenance for hardware upgrades.

Software Developer & IT Support

June 2014 - March 2017

Terinea Ltd, Bexhill-On-Sea

- Full time Java software developer building an enterprise retail platform deployed across the UK using Java, PostgreSQL, Google Web Toolkit, Tomcat, Ant and SVN.
- To improve internal development, I created a lightweight Java application for generating user interfaces which automatically integrated with database tables halving interface development time and reducing maintenance time by employing a standard format.

Projects

Project: Full-Stack Website, API and Blog

Technologies Used: Ubuntu, Nginx, Docker, React, HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, GitHub

- Created a script to generate wildcard certificates for all subdomains
- Personal portfolio auto-deployed using GitHub Actions on mainline commit
- React frontend interface populates data using an internal route to the API

Project: Home Network and Lab

Technologies Used: Ubuntu, pfSense, FreeNAS, Docker, Pi-Hole, Windows Server 2016

- Deployed and secured home network using pfSense, Pi-hole and Squid
- Experimenting with security on Windows Server and client systems on FreeNAS VMs
- Self-hosting services like GitLab, Deluge and SMB with an interest in NextCloud

Interests and Hobbies

Cycling helps me clear my mind and keeps me in good shape which is very much required when working stationary for extended periods of time.

Audiobooks have given me a new way of absorbing information and is now one of my favourite habits to indulge in. "The power of habit" had a profound effect on me and has inspired me to start "Atomic habits" and "The 5am club" with "Seveneves" ready on the shelf.

References

Available upon request